# Maxim Zorin — JavaScript Developer

- maxim.zorin@gmail.com
- LinkedIn: maximzorin
- Saint Petersburg, Russia

Most of my experience has been working for large international companies Zodiac Systems (now part of Orion Innovation), Quest Software (Dell), and JetBrains. Currently, I am in the JavaScript stack. I have a master's degree in Mathematics and CS from Moscow State Pedagogical University.

I'm deeply into JavaScript, and more I'm a JS fan. I have experience with other languages, including Python, and I'm sure JavaScript is the best.

I love spending time with my family, also I enjoy traveling, hiking, canoeing, and playing board games.

## Experience

### IT: Programming, Management, Testing

- 2018-2021 Zodiac Systems Lead JS Developer
- 2013-2018 Zodiac Systems Head JS Technologies
- 2012-2013 JetBrains Senior UI Developer
- 2010-2012 Zodiac Systems Senior JS Developer
- 2006-2010 Quest Software Senior Software Developer
- 2004-2006 Quest Software C# Developer
- 2002-2004 Quest Software Head Quality Assurance
- 2000-2001 Novalumen Lead Quality Assurance
- 1999-2000 Goodwin Webmaster

### Web and JavaScript projects

#### Last decade

- Embedded JS dev, web dev, and lead for solutions in Interactive TV, customer demos, internal web portals.
- Web dev a new version control system.
- Teach EcmaScript and Node courses in Polytech.

#### The 2000s

- Custom dev Active Roles, JavaScripting ActiveDirectory and Windows.
- ASP.NET web dev (developer, QA head) user provisioning, self-service management and security, management ActiveDirectory, recovery Exchange, customize SharePoint.
- Web dev tatastudio.ru Tatasutdio film production company
- QA the 2nd version of beeline.ru, one of the first interactive websites on the Internet.

#### Past millennium

Web dev 1st version goodwin-gmc.com registration and comprehensive legal services



## Education

#### Contribution

- 2013-2021 Anichkov Lyceum (school) Computer Science Teacher
- 2014-2018 SPB Polytechnic University JavaScript Teacher
- 1995-1999 Moscow City University Computer Science Teacher

#### Graduated

1992-1997 Moscow Pedagogical State University
Master of Science, Mathematics and Computer Science

## Skills

#### IT

- JavaScript full stack: FE, BE, Embedded, Testing, Automation, Vanilla dialect
- In active: Python, HTML, CSS, SQL, UML, and Markdown
- In background: Pascal, Delphi, C#, Perl, SSI, PHP, ASP.NET, VBScript, and PowerShell
- Draw and read: UML, SADT, and other diagrams
- OS: Windows (from 3.1), Linux (Ubuntu, Mint)
- Management: up to 20 people team
- Teach CS experience: Upper primary schools, College, University

#### Soft

Problem solving, Open mind, most of 4K

#### Languages

- English B1
- Russian fluent

#### Interests

- Mainly: Fatherhood
- Outdoors: Hiking, Canoeing, Active games
- Indoors: Board games (especially tafl, chess, go), Card games (primarily poker)

https://mxn42.github.io/cv/en/